<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
 *
 * This help file was generated from detectSURFFeatures.sci using help_from_sci().
 *
 -->

<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="detectSURFFeatures" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:scilab="http://www.scilab.org"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <refnamediv>
    <refname>detectSURFFeatures</refname>
    <refpurpose>This function is used to detect SURF(Speeded Up Robust Features) Features in a grayscale Image.</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>


<refsynopsisdiv>
   <title>Calling Sequence</title>
   <synopsis>
   result = detectSURFFeatures(Image);
   result = detectSURFFeatures(Image, Name, Value, ...)
   
   </synopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsection>
   <title>Parameters</title>
   <variablelist>
   <varlistentry><term>result:</term>
      <listitem><para> SURFPoints struct which contains Location of KeyPoints, Orientation, Metric, SignOfLaplacian, Scale and Count of the features.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>Image :</term>
      <listitem><para>  Input image, specified as a A-by-N 2D grayscale.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>MetricThreshold :</term>
      <listitem><para> (Optional) With default value equal to 1000, it is to be specified as a scalar. Every interest point detected has a strength associated with it. In case, only the stronget ones are needed, this parameter has to be given a larger value. To get more no of interest points/blobs, it is to be reduced.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>NumOctaves :</term>
      <listitem><para> (Optional)With default value equal to 3, it is to be specified as a scalar. Larger the number of octaves, larger is the size of blobs detected. This is because higher octave use large sized filters. Value must be an integer scalar in between 1 and 4.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>NumScaleLevels :</term>
      <listitem><para> (Optional)With default value equal to 4, it is to be specified as a scalar. It denotes the number of scale level for each octave. The Value must be an integer scalar greater than or equal to 3.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>ROI :</term>
      <listitem><para> (Optional) Region Of Interest. This is taken as a vector [u v width height]. When specified, the function detects the key points within region of area width*height with u and v being the top left corner coordinates.</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Description</title>
   <para>
This function return the SURF(Speeded Up Robust Features) Interest Points for a 2D Grayscale image. It is scale- and rotation- invariant point detector and descriptor and its application include Camera Calibration, 3D Reconstruction, Object Recognition to name a few.
   </para>
   <para>
</para>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Examples</title>
   <programlisting role="example"><![CDATA[
image = imread('sample.jpg');
results = detectSURFFeatures(image);

   ]]></programlisting>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Authors</title>
   <simplelist type="vert">
   <member>Shashank Shekhar</member>
   </simplelist>
</refsection>
</refentry>
